Hi, name is John Stewart and this is how to find north with or without a compass.
If you're trying to find north you can do it many different ways.
You can do it using a compass, just find a compass match the red arrows up, and you're going to walk north.
If you don't happen to have a compass, you can do this several other ways.
You can find a tree with moss on it, moss always grows on the south side, so walk the other side.
You can do this at night by using the north star, find the north star and that's going to lead you the way.
Other ways you can do this is watch the sun rise and set, the sun rises in the east, sets in the west, so if you can be up at those hours it will help you guide and find north or south.
If you can't do that you can find it other ways.
True north and magnetic north they're very similar, they're very few degrees separate these.
But most maps are set up to use true north.
True north points directly north and magnetic north is going to be off just a little.
Magnetic north is going to point towards your north poles and your south poles on the globe, okay.
But maps are set up to use true north unless you're right on an agnotic line and at that point it's going to use magnetic north.
But these are the many different ways you can find north.